class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> aquaculture_engineering = [

  QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary purpose of aeration in aquaculture ponds?",
      options: [
        "A. To increase water temperature",
        "B. To decrease dissolved oxygen levels",
        "C. To promote algal growth",
        "D. To increase dissolved oxygen levels"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'Aeration is used to increase the dissolved oxygen levels in the water, essential for the well-being of aquatic organisms.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. Which of the following is a commonly used material for constructing aquaculture ponds?",
      options: [
        "A. Concrete",
        "B. Wood",
        "C. Plastic",
        "D. All of the above"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'Aquaculture ponds can be constructed using various materials such as concrete, wood, or plastic, depending on the specific requirements and conditions.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. What is the purpose of a settling basin in aquaculture systems?",
      options: [
        "A. To increase water temperature",
        "B. To remove suspended solids",
        "C. To promote algal growth",
        "D. To increase dissolved oxygen levels"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A settling basin is designed to remove suspended solids from the water, improving water quality by reducing turbidity.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. What is the ideal pH range for most aquaculture species?",
      options: [
        "A. 2-4",
        "B. 5-7",
        "C. 7-9",
        "D. 10-12"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'The ideal pH range for most aquaculture species is between 7 and 9, providing a suitable environment for their growth and reproduction.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. What role does a biofilter play in aquaculture systems?",
      options: [
        "A. Oxygenation",
        "B. Nutrient removal",
        "C. Temperature control",
        "D. Pest control"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A biofilter is used for nutrient removal, breaking down harmful substances like ammonia produced by aquatic organisms.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. Which parameter is crucial for monitoring in recirculating aquaculture systems (RAS)?",
      options: [
        "A. pH",
        "B. Water temperature",
        "C. Dissolved oxygen",
        "D. All of the above"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'Monitoring pH, water temperature, and dissolved oxygen is essential in RAS to maintain optimal conditions for aquatic organisms.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. What is the purpose of a water intake screen in aquaculture facilities?",
      options: [
        "A. To prevent predators",
        "B. To enhance water clarity",
        "C. To filter debris and large particles",
        "D. To reduce water temperature"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A water intake screen is used to filter out debris and large particles, preventing them from entering the aquaculture facility.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. Which type of pump is commonly used for water circulation in aquaculture ponds?",
      options: [
        "A. Diaphragm pump",
        "B. Centrifugal pump",
        "C. Reciprocating pump",
        "D. Gear pump"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Centrifugal pumps are frequently employed for water circulation in aquaculture ponds due to their efficiency and simplicity.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. What is the purpose of adding lime to aquaculture ponds?",
      options: [
        "A. To decrease pH",
        "B. To enhance water clarity",
        "C. To increase alkalinity",
        "D. To promote algal growth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Adding lime to aquaculture ponds increases alkalinity, helping to stabilize pH and provide a suitable environment for aquatic organisms.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. In aquaculture, what does the term 'polyculture' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. Cultivating multiple fish species in the same pond",
        "B. Using only one type of feed",
        "C. Maintaining a single species in the pond",
        "D. Growing plants alongside fish"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Polyculture involves cultivating multiple fish species in the same pond, promoting biodiversity and maximizing resource utilization.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. What is the primary function of a fish grading system in aquaculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Sorting fish by size",
        "B. Determining fish species",
        "C. Separating males and females",
        "D. Assessing fish health"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'A fish grading system is used to sort fish based on size, helping manage stocking density and optimize growth conditions.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. What is the purpose of aeration diffusers in aquaculture ponds?",
      options: [
        "A. To decrease water temperature",
        "B. To increase suspended solids",
        "C. To reduce dissolved oxygen levels",
        "D. To improve oxygen transfer"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'Aeration diffusers enhance oxygen transfer by breaking down bubbles, improving dissolved oxygen levels in aquaculture ponds.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. Which of the following factors can negatively impact water quality in aquaculture ponds?",
      options: [
        "A. Low stocking density",
        "B. Excessive feeding",
        "C. Adequate aeration",
        "D. Clear water"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Excessive feeding can lead to nutrient overload and negatively impact water quality in aquaculture ponds.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. What is the purpose of a fish counter in aquaculture facilities?",
      options: [
        "A. Monitoring water temperature",
        "B. Counting fish during harvesting",
        "C. Regulating pH levels",
        "D. Controlling aeration"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A fish counter is used for counting fish during harvesting, aiding in inventory management and population assessment.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. What role does dissolved oxygen play in aquaculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Promoting algal growth",
        "B. Enhancing water clarity",
        "C. Supporting fish respiration",
        "D. Preventing nutrient buildup"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Dissolved oxygen is crucial in supporting fish respiration, and maintaining optimal levels is essential for the health of aquatic organisms.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. In aquaculture, what is the purpose of a settling tank?",
      options: [
        "A. Providing shelter for fish",
        "B. Removing suspended solids",
        "C. Enhancing water temperature",
        "D. Promoting algal growth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A settling tank is designed to remove suspended solids from water, contributing to improved water quality in aquaculture systems.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. What is the primary function of a fish transportation tank in aquaculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Storing fish for an extended period",
        "B. Facilitating fish reproduction",
        "C. Transporting fish to different locations",
        "D. Promoting algal growth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A fish transportation tank is used for transporting fish to different locations, ensuring their safe and efficient movement within the aquaculture facility.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. What is the purpose of adding probiotics to aquaculture ponds?",
      options: [
        "A. Decreasing dissolved oxygen levels",
        "B. Enhancing water clarity",
        "C. Promoting beneficial microbial activity",
        "D. Controlling fish diseases"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Adding probiotics to aquaculture ponds promotes beneficial microbial activity, contributing to a healthy environment and disease control.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. Why is proper aeration important in aquaculture?",
      options: [
        "A. To decrease water temperature",
        "B. To reduce pH levels",
        "C. To improve dissolved oxygen levels",
        "D. To inhibit algal growth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Proper aeration is essential to improve dissolved oxygen levels in aquaculture ponds, supporting the respiratory needs of aquatic organisms.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. What is the primary purpose of a fish quarantine tank in aquaculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Facilitating fish reproduction",
        "B. Monitoring water temperature",
        "C. Treating fish diseases",
        "D. Controlling aeration"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A fish quarantine tank is used for isolating and treating fish with diseases, preventing the spread of illnesses within the aquaculture facility.'
  ),

  ];